{"tossups": [{"question": "1. This poet never published sections titled \u201cOverture\u201d and \u201cCanticle of St.\u00a0John the Baptist\u201d for one poem, whose first section ends by describing a \u201cmoribund star, which shall never shine!\u201d That poetic retelling of the marriage of Salom\u00e9 was written over a period of 34 years until this author\u2019s death. In an elegy, this poet called one author the \u201cemblem fatal\u201d of \u201cour joyousness.\u201d That \u201cFuneral Toast\u201d by this author of the H\u00e9rodiade is dedicated to Th\u00e9ophile (*) Gautier [tay-oh-FEEL goat-YAY]. In a poem, this poet asks the title creature \u201cif the women of your glosses / are the phantoms of your fabulous desires.\u201d That poem begins with the half-goat speaker stating, \u201cThese nymphs / I would perpetuate them,\u201dand was set to music by Claude Debussy. For 10 points, name this French Symbolist poet of \u201cAfternoon of a Faun.\u201d", "answer": "St\u00e9phane Mallarm\u00e9 &lt;SB, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "St\u00e9phane Mallarm\u00e9 &lt;SB, <b><u>Poetry&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["St\u00e9phane Mallarm\u00e9 &lt;SB, Poetry&gt;", "Poetry&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "2. Description acceptable. A \u201cmemorial\u201d on \u201cbones\u201d expresses regret that Gaozu\u2019s officials could not implement this policy because they could not comprehend the \u201cway of the ancient kings.\u201d An instance of this policy caused Ennin to return to his home country. Three separate implementations of this policy are referred to as the \u201cThree Disasters of Wu.\u201d Double taxes were implemented on many individuals as part of a \u201cGreat\u201d instance of this policy encouraged by Han Yu and intended to recoup funds after a campaign against the (*) Uighurs. It was implemented by Emperor Wuzong, who carried it out with the stated reasons of restoring Confucian values from foreign influence, though largely also to increase tax revenues through expropriation. For 10 points, identify this policy under which the Tang dynasty attempted to crush the influence of a religion that taught the Eightfold Path.", "answer": "suppression of Buddhism in China [accept any answer referring to Buddhists being oppressed or equivalents; accept specific varieties of Buddhism] &lt;WA, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>suppression of Buddhism in China &lt;WA, World History&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>any answer referring to Buddhists being oppressed</u></b> or equivalents; accept <b><u>specific varieties of Buddhism</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["suppression of Buddhism in China &lt;WA, World History&gt;", "suppression of Buddhism in China &lt;WA, World History&gt;", "any answer referring to Buddhists being oppressed", "specific varieties of Buddhism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "3. Easier processing of this crop was enabled by a mutation in the nud gene, which expresses this plant\u2019s \u201cnaked\u201d variant. The Middle PPNB period has evidence of cultivation of this crop\u2019s \u201ctwo-row\u201d and \u201csix-row\u201d varieties. This crop\u2019s main domesticated cultivar, Hordeum vulgare, was bred from its original wild variety, Hordeum spontaneum, to have less brittle spikes. This is one of the three Neolithic \u201cfounder crops\u201d along with einkorn and emmer. It\u2019s not wheat, but the first usage of (*) pearling to strip bran was for this crop. In ancient Egypt, this crop was broken up, mixed with water, and left in an exposed vessel. It\u2019s the crop from which the original Scottish whiskey was distilled. For 10 points, name this cereal grain that was malted to make beer in ancient Mesopotamia.", "answer": "barley [accept Hordeum vulgare until read] &lt;AA, Archaeology&gt;", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>barley &lt;AA, Archaeology&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Hordeum vulgare</u></b> until read]", "acceptable": ["barley &lt;AA, Archaeology&gt;", "barley &lt;AA, Archaeology&gt;", "Hordeum vulgare"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "4. A work set in this polity begins with an address to the Earl of Mulgrave and contains a monologue that opens \u201cWhen I consider life, \u2019tis all a cheat / Yet fool\u2019d with hope, men favour the deceit.\u201d Documents called the \u201cMutiny Papers\u201d were used to write a historical novel about this polity\u2019s final ruler by William Dalrymple. The only woman in this polity to have coinage struck in her name is depicted in the novel The Twentieth Wife. A struggle between four sons, including one who loves Indamora, to take the throne of this polity is depicted in a (*) 1678 play by John Dryden which includes a character named Dara-shah. The first ruler of this empire wrote a lengthy epic that discusses his exile from the Ferghana Valley, his conquest of Kabul, and his defeat of Ibrahim Lodi at Panipat. For 10 points, name this empire whose first ruler wrote the Baburnama.", "answer": "Mughal empire (The Dryden play is Aureng-zebe and is referred to in the first clue.) &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mughal empire &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Mughal empire &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;", "Mughal empire &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "The Dryden play is Aureng-zebe and is referred to in the first clue."}, {"question": "5. An anti-Semitic pamphlet signed only as \u201cSatan\u201d alleged that the Rothschilds took advantage of quick knowledge of this battle\u2019s outcome to play the stock market. Scavengers traveled to this battle\u2019s site to pull teeth from the mouth of corpses and sell them as dentures called this battle\u2019s namesake \u201cteeth.\u201d The man who won the race to inform one government of this battle was known only as Mr. C, who shouted \u201cVictory, sir! Victory!\u201d One of the winning side\u2019s subordinate officers apocryphally shouted \u201cBy God, sir, I\u2019ve lost my (*) leg!\u201d, to which his commander replied \u201cBy God, sir, so you have.\u201d Pierre Cambronne reportedly shouted \u201cMerde!\u201d in response to one event here. The losing side\u2019s army fled while yelling \u201cThe Guard retreats! Save yourselves!\u201d, referring to the destruction of the Grande Arm\u00e9e\u2019s Imperial Guard. For 10 points, name this battle at which Marshal Ney supposedly bellowed \u201cwatch how a Marshal of France dies\u201d after Napoleon was legendarily stricken with hemorrhoids in Belgium.", "answer": "Battle of Waterloo &lt;AA, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Battle of Waterloo &lt;AA, Continental History&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Battle of Waterloo &lt;AA, Continental History&gt;", "Battle of Waterloo &lt;AA, Continental History&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "6. Due to this people\u2019s tradition of matrilineal descent, the Treaty of Middle Plantation was signed by the female chief Cockacoeske [koh-ka-koh-ess-kay]. The construction of Fort Charles, Fort James, and Fort Royal preceded an assault that resulted in the deportation of this tribe\u2019s males over age 11 and the installation of Necotowance [neck-oh-toh-wants] as a tributary chief. This tribe was led by a paramount chief reported to by subordinate chiefs called weroances [weh-row-ahnt-siz], among whom was a leader of the (*) Pamunkey; that leader would later order a massacre that Richard Pace was warned about by a Christianized member of this tribe. A series of wars between this tribe and English settlers involved the chieftain Opechancanough [oh-pah-CHAHN-kah-noh]. Following his daughter\u2019s capture by Samuel Argall, this tribe\u2019s most famous chief acceded to her being allowed to marry John Rolfe and stay in Jamestown. For 10 points, name this confederacy of Algonquian-speaking tribes whose namesake chieftain fathered Pocahontas.", "answer": "Powhatan Confederacy [or Tsenacommacah; accept Pamunkey until read] &lt;AA, US History&gt;", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Powhatan Confederacy &lt;AA, US History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Tsenacommacah</u></b>; accept <b><u>Pamunkey</u></b> until read]", "acceptable": ["Powhatan Confederacy &lt;AA, US History&gt;", "Powhatan Confederacy &lt;AA, US History&gt;", "Tsenacommacah", "Pamunkey"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "7. A version of this activity done while burning leaves is described in the poem \u201cHours in the Garden.\u201d A poem titled for this activity ends with the line \u201cAnd silently they vanish in the sand\u201d and precedes \u201cA Toccata of Bach\u201d among poems from one author\u2019s \u201cstudent years.\u201d For several months, a character ceases practicing this activity, choosing instead to throw stalks in a bamboo grove. A \u201cholograph translation\u201d from Latin prefaces a history of this activity that credits its invention to a certain (*) Bastian Perrot of Calw, and is written by Ziegenhalss. This activity, which is the \u201craison d\u2019\u00eatre\u201d of a province named for a Parnassian spring, is described as an \u201cact of synthesis\u201d in which such disciplines as philosophy, math, and music collide, so a Music Master guides a boy who learns to master it. For 10 points, name this activity played in Castalia by the title Magister Ludi of a Hermann Hesse novel.", "answer": "the glass-bead game [or Das Glasperlenspiel or equivalents; prompt on game or board game] &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the glass-bead game &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Das Glasperlenspiel</u></b> or equivalents; prompt on <u>game</u> or <u>board game</u>]", "acceptable": ["the glass-bead game &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "glass-bead game &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "Das Glasperlenspiel"], "promptable": ["game", "board game"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "8. A historian called \u201cSimocatta\u201d wrote an account of an event in which one of these two powers backed a pretender who came from one of the Seven Great Houses. Partly because these two powers could not agree on the status of Suania, a \u201cfifty-year\u201d peace between them was eventually ignored. Major clashes between these two powers frequently centered on the border fortress of Dara. They carried out proxy conflicts through such clients as the Ghassanid and Lakhmid dynasties. The (*) Lazic and Iberian Wars were fought between these two powers, with the latter being concluded by the Treaty of Perpetual Peace. These powers clashed during a non-BCE era Battle of Nineveh, at which part of the True Cross was recovered by Heraclius; shortly after, both were overrun by Arab invaders. For 10 points, name these two powers led by contemporaries Khusrau and Justinian, both called \u201cthe Great.\u201d", "answer": "(Eastern) Roman empire AND Sassanid empire [accept Rome or Byzantine empire or Byzantium in place of \u201cRoman empire\u201d; accept Persian empire or Sassanian empire in place of \u201cSassanid\u201d empire, but do not accept or prompt on \u201cParthia\u201d or \u201cAchaemenid Persia\u201d] &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Roman empire AND Sassanid empire &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Rome</u></b> or <b><u>Byzantine empire</u></b> or <b><u>Byzantium</u></b> in place of \u201cRoman empire; accept <b><u>Persian empire</u></b> or <b><u>Sassanian empire</u></b> in place of \u201cSassanid\u201d empire, but do not or <b><u>or prompt on \u201cParthia</u></b> or <b><u>Achaemenid Persia</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Roman empire AND Sassanid empire &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "Roman empire AND Sassanid empire &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "Rome", "Byzantine empire", "Byzantium", "Persian empire", "Sassanian empire", "or prompt on \u201cParthia", "Achaemenid Persia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Eastern"}, {"question": "9. Lines created by this literary effort, such as \u201cThe sea had soakt his heart through,\u201d sparked one author\u2019s \u201cparticular delight\u201d according to the accounts of Charles Gordon Clarke. This literary effort essentially outmoded the only earlier similar work in the same language, done by Arthur Hall, and helped reduce reliance on a Latin version by Lorenzo Valla. An author\u2019s original line \u201cYet I never judge what Men could mean,\u201d which was replaced by a line ending with \u201cpure serene,\u201d indicated a preference for the product of this effort over similar work by (*) Alexander Pope. The man who made this literary effort spoke out \u201cloud and bold\u201d according to a poem titled for it, which mentions a \u201cstout Cortez\u201d and opens \u201cMuch have I travelled in realms of gold.\u201d For 10 points, identify this 17th-century rendering of the Iliad and Odyssey into English, which Keats wrote about \u201cOn First Looking Into.\u201d", "answer": "George Chapman\u2019s translations of Homer [accept Chapman\u2019s Homer or \u201cOn First Looking into Chapman\u2019s Homer\u201d; accept George Chapman\u2019s translation of the Iliad and Odyssey until \u201cIliad\u201d; accept The Odyssey in the first sentence and prompt after; prompt on the Iliad until read; prompt on translating Homer or similar partial answers by asking \u201cby who?\u201d, since Chapman is required] &lt;WA, Literary Legacy&gt;", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>George Chapman\u2019s translations of Homer &lt;WA, Literary Legacy&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Chapman\u2019s Homer</u></b> or <b><u>On First Looking into Chapman\u2019s Homer</u></b>; accept <b><u>George Chapman\u2019s translation of the Iliad</u></b> or <b><u>Odyssey</u></b> until \u201cIliad; accept <b><u>The Odyssey in the first sentence</u></b> or <b><u>prompt after</u></b>; prompt on the <u>Iliad</u> until read; prompt on <u>translating Homer</u> or <u>similar partial answers by asking \u201cby who?\u201d,</u> since Chapman is required]", "acceptable": ["George Chapman\u2019s translations of Homer &lt;WA, Literary Legacy&gt;", "George Chapman\u2019s translations of Homer &lt;WA, Literary Legacy&gt;", "Chapman\u2019s Homer", "On First Looking into Chapman\u2019s Homer", "George Chapman\u2019s translation of the Iliad", "Odyssey", "The Odyssey in the first sentence", "prompt after"], "promptable": ["Iliad", "translating Homer", "similar partial answers by asking \u201cby who?\u201d,"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "10. A character in this play remarks that hysteria is a \u201ccommon denominator of the female nature\u201d and that the \u201ctest of a man is his ability to cope with it.\u201d An author\u2019s note in this play likens a character\u2019s face during her unique laugh to that of a seal opening its mouth and expecting a fish. After addressing a girl as \u201cMiss Thin-Standing-Up-Female-Buddha\u201d in this play, a man describes his \u201cspooks\u201d to her, which she compares to her own \u201cblue devils.\u201d A character in this play completes his (*) final poem shortly before dying of a stroke and claims to be the world\u2019s oldest poet. Hannah Jelkes tries to get a room for her and her grandfather at the Costa Verde Hotel in this play, but runs into problems with its owner, Maxine Faulk. For 10 points, name this Tennessee Williams\u2019 play set in Mexico, which features the disgraced Reverend T. Lawrence Shannon.", "answer": "Night of the Iguana &lt;SB, Drama&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Night of the Iguana &lt;SB, Drama&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Night of the Iguana &lt;SB, Drama&gt;", "Night of the Iguana &lt;SB, Drama&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "11. A journal espousing this theory was founded by Christopher Chase-Dunn. A proponent of this theory wrote a notable urban history of Cairo subtitled \u201c1001 Years of the City Victorious\u201d and used a city-focused approach to extend this theory to the era of Mongol domination; that is Janet Abu-Lughod. A work subtitled \u201cFive Hundred Years or Five Thousand?\u201d, which argues that the structure this theory describes has existed longer than originally posited, was written by Barry Gills and Andre Gunder Frank. The originator of this theory suggested that the (*) \u201clong 16th century\u201d between the discovery of America and the English Civil War was critical for the spread of capitalism, leading to a global division of labor after the decline of feudalism. For 10 points, name this view of history which divides nations into \u201ccore\u201d and \u201cperiphery,\u201d first advocated by Immanuel Wallerstein.", "answer": "world-systems theory &lt;EM, Phil/SS&gt;", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>world-systems theory &lt;EM, Phil/SS&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["world-systems theory &lt;EM, Phil/SS&gt;", "world-systems theory &lt;EM, Phil/SS&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "12. A character in this novel does a cartwheel in front of a woman on the beach because he thinks she looks like a Winslow Homer painting. In this novel, a delusional man who believes he is a professional baseball player is kept to run around the field as a team mascot by the Giants. A character in this novel tries to send his small daughter away from a strike to safety, but jumps on her train at the last minute. That character, Tateh, rises from cutting out paper silhouettes to becoming a (*) movie tycoon styled \u201cThe Baron\u201d and marrying one character, whose husband died on the Lusitania. Firemen led by Will Conklin vandalize the Model\u00a0T\u00a0Ford of Coalhouse Walker in this novel, which also features Younger Brother, Mother, and Father. For 10 points, Emma Goldman and Harry Houdini appear in what novel set in the early 20th century by E. L. Doctorow?", "answer": "Ragtime &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ragtime &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ragtime &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;", "Ragtime &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "13. Specific name required. A likely-fabricated stone inscription purporting to record a journey from this place was found by a farmer in Minnesota and named for the settlement of Kensington. An accidental landing in this place south of places named for \u201cflat rocks\u201d and \u201cforests\u201d is recorded by Ari the Wise. The oldest known reference to this location notes that it is named for objects that \u201cgrow wildly,\u201d and is found in the Descriptio Insulae Aquilonis within the Gesta Hammaburgensis of (*) Adam of Bremen. Etymological disputes over this place\u2019s name trace it to a word for pastures or, alternatively, to fermented berries or grapes. The settlement of Straumfjord was built here by Thorfinn Karlsefni. It\u2019s unclear whether L\u2019Anse Aux Meadows is equivalent to this location or a repair station for visiting ships. For 10 points, what name did Leif Ericson give to areas of North America he settled?", "answer": "Vinland [or Wineland or Vineland] &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Vinland &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Wineland</u></b> or <b><u>Vineland</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Vinland &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;", "Vinland &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;", "Wineland", "Vineland"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "14. Works of journalism covering this product were attacked by a full-page editorial by The New York Times\u2019 Tim Golden, as well as by LSU dean Jerry Ceppos, whose letters to the Washington Post were not printed. Nick Schou\u2019s book Kill the Messenger is the basis of a documentary about a reporter who covered this product, who focused primarily on Ricky Ross, Norwin Meneses, and Oscar Danilo Blandon in his writings for the San Jose Mercury News. A series called \u201cDark Alliance\u201d profiling the (*) trade in this product was written by a journalist who shot himself in 2004. A former SNCC official was found with this product in the Vista Hotel in 1990, precluding his mayoral re-election. This product\u2019s mass importation was blamed on the Contras and by Gary Webb. Washington D.C. mayor Marion Barry was infamously caught using, for 10 points, what drug that Keith Haring called \u201cwhack\u201d on a mural?", "answer": "crack cocaine [or freebase cocaine; prompt on cocaine or coke or drugs or illicit substances or less specific answers] &lt;EM, US History&gt;", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>crack cocaine &lt;EM, US History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>freebase cocaine</u></b>; prompt on <u>cocaine</u> or <u>coke</u> or <u>drugs</u> or <u>illicit substances</u> or <u>less specific answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["crack cocaine &lt;EM, US History&gt;", "crack cocaine &lt;EM, US History&gt;", "freebase cocaine"], "promptable": ["cocaine", "coke", "drugs", "illicit substances", "less specific answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "15. This man unsuccessfully tried to convince Charlie Chaplin to star in his never-produced \u201cgreat super-ballet of New York\u201d featuring typewriters and radio, Chronkite\u2019s Clocks. This writer lambasted detective stories in the essay \u201cWho Cares Who Killed Roger Ackroyd?\u201d and contrasted comparative literature and connoisseurship with the title concept in \u201cThe Historical Interpretation of Literature.\u201d This author wrote a work whose title derives from \u201cMaryland, My Maryland\u201d and a work whose name refers to a (*) Villiers de l\u2019Isle Adam [veel-YAY duh LEEL ah-DOM] play; in the latter work, this husband of Mary McCarthy provided an overview of Symbolist literature. This author of To the Finland Station included figures like Albion Tourgee and Harriet Beecher Stowe in another work highlighting Civil War literature. For 10 points, name this American literary critic who wrote Axel\u2019s Castle and Patriotic Gore.", "answer": "Edmund Wilson &lt;JC, Essays/Crit&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Edmund Wilson &lt;JC, <b><u>Essays/Crit&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Edmund Wilson &lt;JC, Essays/Crit&gt;", "Essays/Crit&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "16. In this country, the murder of Altab Ali by three teenagers sparked massive outrage. Operation Swamp 81 targeted immigrant-heavy neighborhoods in this country according to the \u201cSus law.\u201d Until 1997, immigrants married to this country\u2019s citizens were subject to the Primary Purpose Rule. After a series of riots here, a shift from \u201crace relations\u201d to \u201ccommunity relations\u201d was heralded by the Scarman Report. The Bhola cyclone prompted a wave of immigration to this country, which took in the plurality of Asians expelled by (*) Idi Amin. An elderly woman whose mailbox was filled with human waste was discussed in a speech against this country\u2019s Race Relations Act that cited a passage in the Aeneid about the River Tiber \u201cfoaming with blood.\u201d Enoch Powell spoke against immigration to, for 10 points, what country where many Bangladeshis live in the Brick Lane neighborhood in East London?", "answer": "Great Britain [or the UK or the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland] &lt;EM, British/Other History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Great Britain &lt;EM, British/Other <b><u>History&gt;</u></b> [or the <b><u>UK</u></b> or the <b><u>United Kingdom of Great Britain</u></b> or <b><u>Northern Ireland</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Great Britain &lt;EM, British/Other History&gt;", "History&gt;", "UK", "United Kingdom of Great Britain", "Northern Ireland"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "17. This U.S. state names a poem that opens by mentioning a \u201cBarque of phosphor,\u201d which is titled for an allegorical medieval French tale called a fabliau. A characteristic creature of this state \u201cwhimpers and speaks in the throat / of the Indian Princess\u201d according to a poem titled for this state by Elizabeth Bishop. A poem set in this state describes an ambiguous figure who \u201cmade the sky / Acutest at its vanishing\u201d and \u201cmeasured the hour to its solitude.\u201d That poem set here addresses a \u201cpale\u201d friend with the phrase (*) \u201cO!\u00a0Blessed rage for order\u201d before speaking of \u201cghostlier demarcations, keener sounds.\u201d In a poem set in this state, the speaker asks his friend Ramon Fernandez if he witnessed what happened after \u201cshe sang beyond the genius of the sea.\u201d For 10 points, name this state, the setting of Wallace Stevens\u2019 \u201cThe Idea of Order at Key West.\u201d", "answer": "Florida [accept \u201cFabliau of Florida\u201d] &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Florida &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Fabliau of Florida</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Florida &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "Florida &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "Fabliau of Florida"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "18. A photograph taken during this war shows a group of captured soldiers huddled under an outdoor shower. Another photo taken during it shows a group of refugees crossing the bombed-out Allenby Bridge. An iconic photograph taken during this war shows a man whose face was scarred by a bayonet during the Battle of Ammunition Hill. Another photo from this war shows a bearded man holding a scroll under his left arm while holding a horn to his lips. A photograph taken during this conflict by (*) David Rubinger shows six soldiers looking upwards from a low angle, one of whom has taken their helmet off, and is titled Paratroopers at the Western Wall. Another depicts three officials walking victoriously through the Lion Gate into the Old City, one of whom is the eyepatch-wearing Moshe Dayan. For 10 points, name this short 1967 conflict between Israel and its neighbors.", "answer": "Six-Day War [accept 1967 War until \u201c1967\u201d is read] &lt;EM, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Six-Day War &lt;EM, World History&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>1967 War</u></b> until \u201c1967\u201d is read]", "acceptable": ["Six-Day War &lt;EM, World History&gt;", "Six-Day War &lt;EM, World History&gt;", "1967 War"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "19. In a novel with this title, several shipwrecked characters find themselves cooped up in the house of the eminent art historian Kreutzner and his servant Licht. A John Banville novel with this title is the second in his Frames trilogy featuring Freddie Montgomery. The Anne Frank-like Amy Bellette and the writer E. I. Lonoff are recurring characters in two different Philip Roth novels with this word in their title. White hires Blue to investigate a man named Black in a book with this noun as its title, which comes between City of (*) Glass and The Locked Room in Paul Auster\u2019s New York Trilogy. This noun titles a play in which Pastor Manders supposedly sets fire to an orphanage, and in which the syphilitic Oswald is euthanized by his mother Mrs. Alving, who is haunted by the specter of her late husband. For 10 points, give this spooky noun that titles a Henrik Ibsen play.", "answer": "ghosts [accept Exit Ghost or The Ghost Writer] &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ghosts &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Exit Ghost</u></b> or <b><u>The Ghost Writer</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["ghosts &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;", "ghosts &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;", "Exit Ghost", "The Ghost Writer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "20. Ancient legitimacy of this modern-day country\u2019s people was asserted by historian Aleks Buda. This country\u2019s writing was standardized in the Conference of Monastir by scholars who led its late 19th- and early 20th-century \u201cNational Awakening.\u201d A leader of this non-China country who created the \u201cdual adversary\u201d wrote 1,600 pages of diaries trying to understand Chinese diplomacy, titled Reflections on China. Consistent sound shift, such as the name of the city of Dyrrhachium and likely borrowings from (*) Doric dialects, lead many linguists to argue that this country\u2019s language is a descendant of Illyrian. Marin Barleti wrote a biography of one of this country\u2019s great leaders. This country\u2019s modern founding father, historian and bishop Fan Noli, also wrote a book on that leader, who struggled against Murad II. For 10 points, name this nation whose first unifier is considered to be Skanderbeg.", "answer": "Albania [or Shqip] &lt;WA, Historiography&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Albania &lt;WA, <b><u>Historiography&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Shqip</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Albania &lt;WA, Historiography&gt;", "Historiography&gt;", "Shqip"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "21. The protagonist of this story mistakes the shadows of people approaching for rabbits, but becomes relieved when he doesn\u2019t see \u201ctheir long menacing ears.\u201d This story quotes from Lord Byron\u2019s \u201cChilde Harold\u2019s Pilgrimage\u201d when describing a character who has not learned that \u201ctempted Fate will leave the loftiest star.\u201d That character is also described as having a \u201clust for war\u201d after he hops on boulders to cross a wide stream and kill an imaginary foe. The protagonist of this story retreats to climb a tree after being thrown to the ground by a (*) soldier whose back he jumped upon and tried to ride like a horse. In this story\u2019s final scene, a child finds the body of a dead woman whose brain is protruding through her forehead and discovers his house is being burned down. For 10 points, name this story about a deaf-mute 6-year-old boy in the middle of a Civil War battlefield, written by Ambrose Bierce.", "answer": "\u201cChickamauga\u201d &lt;SB, Short Fiction&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cChickamauga\u201d &lt;SB, Short Fiction&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cChickamauga\u201d &lt;SB, Short Fiction&gt;", "\u201cChickamauga\u201d &lt;SB, Short Fiction&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "22. Four of this author\u2019s poems were enclosed in a letter to an editor of the Atlantic Monthly, which asked if the editor was not \u201ctoo deeply occupied to say if [this author\u2019s] Verse is alive?\u201d Harvard\u2019s Rare Book Room contains a copy of this author\u2019s original herbarium, which contains over 424 pressed flower specimens that this author collected. The book White Heat recounts the correspondences that took place between this author and mentor (*) Thomas Wentworth Higginson. This author\u2019s sister Lavinia fulfilled her wishes and burned almost all of her letters after her death, but also found over a hundred of her poems and published them. This author would allegedly only wear cotton white dresses and answer visitors at her Homestead house without opening her door. For 10 points name this reclusive American poet, nicknamed the \u201cBelle of Amherst.\u201d", "answer": "Emily Dickinson  &lt;SB, Authors/Bios&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Emily Dickinson  &lt;SB, <b><u>Authors/Bios&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Emily Dickinson  &lt;SB, Authors/Bios&gt;", "Authors/Bios&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "23. In Ralph Ellison\u2019s Invisible Man, the narrator remembers secretly eating this food in class behind the cover of a large World Geography book. The narrator later compares his love for this food to Bledsoe\u2019s \u201cshameless\u201d love for chitterlings and purchases another two of them, though one turns out to be frostbitten. In Omeros, Philoctete grows a garden of this food and later destroys his entire harvest of it to show his ancestors what \u201cit\u2019s like without roots in the world.\u201d In a short story, a lowly red-nosed (*) samurai sees his craving for a soup of this food disappear after he accompanies Toshihito on a trip to his mansion. Nwoye is chastised by Okonkwo because he is unable to properly grow this food, which titles an Akutagawa short story. For 10 points, name this most important crop grown in Umuofia, a sweet-potato like vegetable.", "answer": "yams &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>yams &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["yams &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;", "yams &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "24. This river\u2019s upper basin is the seat of the Przeworsk [pshuh-VORSK] culture, believed to contain elements of the Lugii [LOO-gee] tribal confederation. Historically, the name Aistinmari [EYE-steen-mah-ree] or \u201csea of the Aesti\u201d was given to the large shallow lagoon at this river\u2019s end. It\u2019s generally believed that goods traveling [emphasize] south on the overland Amber Route began their journey south along this river. It\u2019s not in Brittany or near Venice, but the Latin name for a group living along this river, Venedi, provided English with the word \u201cWends.\u201d After the (*) Teutonic Knights forded this river, they built a fortress at Toru\u0144. In an event called the \u201cMiracle\u201d on this River in 1920, five Russian armies were routed by troops under the command of J\u00f3zef Pi\u0142sudski [YOO-zeff peew-SOOD-skee]. For 10 points, name this river that flows past Krakow and Warsaw, the longest in Poland.", "answer": "Vistula River [or Wisla River] &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Vistula River &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Wisla River</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Vistula River &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "Vistula River &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "Wisla River"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}